What did you say?
You mean you sent Genin after Sasuke?
Well, what else could I do?
You know the state that this village is in
right now.
Hey!
Where are you going?
You already have a mission assigned to
you!
I have to go run an errand first.
Be back in a bit.
Don't worry.
Oh, brother...
Summoning Jutsu!
Okay, guys.
Fan out and start searching for Naruto and
Sasuke's scent.
Did you say Naruto and Sasuke?
What's going on?
What happened to the two of them?
I'll explain later.
Right now, time is of the essence.
Right.
Let me know as soon as you pick up their
scent.
I'll be there immediately.
All right.
Scatter!
Well, they did go at each other right
before her eyes.
Guess there's no point in telling her not
to worry.
I hope I'm not too late.
Sasuke!
Are you going to run off again?
So it's you.
Hopeless little knucklehead.
She sent you, huh?
I did everything I could.
I tried, but I couldn't stop him from
leaving the village.
At this point, there's only one person who
can stop him.
Only one who can save him.
Naruto, it's all up to you.
Naruto...
This is a... once-in-a-lifetime request.
Just bring him home.
Please bring Sasuke back to me.
Look at you.
What's with the angry face?
You know, you asked Sakura for advice when
she was here.
So what did she tell you?
Let's go back.
All right.
Why did you... I don't know.
I don't know either.
My body just moved.
There was no time to think.
You have to save Sakura if it's the last
thing you do.
Sasuke...
You... I can hold him
here a little longer.
I lost everything once.
I don't ever want to have to see that
again.
My trusted comrades falling right in front
of me.
Why?
Why are you doing this to us?
I don't get it!
What happened to make you like this?
Why are you doing it?
Why should you care what I do?
It's my concern, not yours.
I have my own path to follow now.
And neither you nor anyone else can steer
me from it.
I will tell you this much.
My days of playing ninja with you kids of
the Leaf Village... are done.
All of them.
They all risked their lives.
And why?
To save you!
Well, wasn't that nice of them.
Sasuke...
Since no one has anything to add,
I saved the most important thing for last.
For as long as I've known him, Sasuke
and I haven't exactly been close buddies.
In fact, I don't really like him at all.
All the same, Sasuke's a ninja belonging
to the Hidden Leaf Village.
He's a comrade.
And I'll put my life on the line to help
him.
That's the way of our village.
Wake up before it's too late!
If I'd stayed with comrades like you,
I'd never have gotten this strong.
Now I'm going to where Orochimaru is.
Are you out of your mind?!
Orochimaru killed the
Third Hokage and did
everything he could to
destroy the Leaf Village!
Whatever it is that
you're expecting from him,
you think he's going to
give it to you for free?!
All he wants is to use your body like a
new suit of clothes!
There'll be nothing of you left!
You'll never get out of there alive!
You think I'll stand by and just let you
throw away your entire life?!
None of that matters now.
The only thing that matters to me is
achieving my goal.
If you insist on getting in my way,
well, then it can't be helped.
Well, if you aren't
going to listen to reason,
then I'll do this by
force if I have to!
What have you got to laugh about?!
I remember you laughing the last time we
met.
The last time?
Remember how thrilled you were at the
thought of beating me to a bloody pulp?
I didn't mean...
I never really wanted that kind of fight!
Even now, I still don't!
I couldn't give a damn what you want.
I'm not going to let you get away with
this!
What is it?
This sudden burst of power...
If that's what I'm capable of now,
wait till I unseal this curse mark.
Imagine the power!
I have woken up, don't you see?
That guy who dreamed of a happy future
full of peace and friendship.
He was the one who was asleep.
That's why I left the village.
That's why I've gone in search of power.
It's not the future I dream of anymore.
Only the past.
That's where my dream lies.
Wow, Itachi!
You nailed every target!
Even the one in the blind spot behind the
rock!
All right!
Now it's my turn!
No, Sasuke.
It's time to go.
What happened to the new shuriken jutsu
you promised to teach me, huh?
It'll have to wait till later.
I have an important mission in the
morning, and I need to prepare for it.
It's time to go.
You're such a big fat liar.
Sorry, Sasuke.
Maybe some other time.
Okay, just watch this!
Hey!
Be careful!
How come the one who twisted his ankle is
the one who's laughing?
Maybe you were just looking for a way to
get out of walking home.
No way, that's not it.
It's just that I can't
stop thinking how I'm
finally going to start at
the academy tomorrow.
What's up?
That building is where father works,
isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
It's headquarters for the Leaf Police
Force.
I was wondering, how
come the crest of the Uchiha
clan is part of the Leaf
Police Force insignia?
Well, what do you know?
You finally noticed.
Of course I did.
Right.
Let me see if I can explain it for you.
It was the Uchiha
clan's earliest ancestors
who established the
police here in the village.
So when they created this symbol for the
organization, they used the family crest.
Since a long time ago, the Uchiha have
always ensured the peace here.
The crest is a testament of our clan's
pride and a way of life centuries old.
Over the years, the Uchiha clan has grown
smaller.
But even now, nearly
all of us are a part of the
force and work to uphold
the peace in this village.
Which is good, because only
the most exceptional of shinobi
can weed out the criminals
hiding among their brethren.
Wow, dad is the coolest.
Are you going to join the force too?
Well, I'm not sure.
Why not?
Boy, when I grow up, I'm definitely going
to enter the police force.
And father's coming to tomorrow's entrance
ceremony.
It's the first step to my dream.
That's right.
You're late, Itachi.
What have you been doing?
Father!
I need to talk to you.
Let's go.
About tomorrow's special mission.
I've decided to go along with you.
Tomorrow?
If you complete tomorrow's
mission, Itachi, your
entrance into Anbu Black
Ops is all but assured.
Do you understand?
You don't have to worry about me out
there.
And more importantly...
Father, you see, tomorrow afternoon is...
This mission tomorrow, it's not just about
you.
Your performance will reflect on our
entire clan.
Actually, I'm going to pass on tomorrow's
mission.
What are you talking about?
That's insanity!
You know how important this is!
You'll do no such thing!
I have to.
Tomorrow is Sasuke's entrance ceremony.
Our family has to attend.
It's customary at the academy.
You received a notice, remember?
Alright, I get it.
I'll be at the academy tomorrow.
Your left leg.
Be sure to ice it.
Okay.
My congratulations to all of you.
You have a lot of hard work ahead of you
as you walk the path of the Shinobi.
But I expect great things.
I know you will do the Leaf Village proud.
Boy, it seems like only yesterday that you
were here for Itachi, huh?
And you're his spitting image.
Thank you for your help with both of my
boys.
Oh, not at all.
It's been a pleasure.
That boy of yours is a true prodigy.
There hasn't been another one like him in
the history of the academy.
Please, you're being too kind.
Nonsense.
We expect big things from you as well,
Sasuke.
Become a fine Shinobi, just like your
older brother.
Yes, father.
Hey, that's Uchiha, right?
Yeah.
Wow, I wonder if he's a genius too.
Yeah, he has to be.
Huh?
Oh man, I thought recess was never going
to get here.
These classes are such a drag.
Shigemaru, you want some?
Seriously, not every single break has to
be a snack break, you know what I mean?
That's my boy.
You'll go far in the Anbu ranks,
no question about it.
It's still not good enough.
I have to do better.
Sasuke, this is your day off, dear.
You need to give your body some rest.
Ow!
You don't have to push yourself so hard.
I know, but they say big brother graduated
from the academy in just a year.
Times have changed, sweetheart.
And your brother is... special.
Alright, these are your report cards for
the first term.
Keep excelling like this and you'll be
just like your brother in no time.
Father, I wanted you to say, that's my
boy, to me.
Come again?
What do you mean you can't participate in
the assembly?
I don't really think you understand your
position.
I'm setting out on a mission tomorrow.
It's the middle of the night.
Why are they up with the lights off?
What are you talking about?
I can't tell you.
The mission is covert.
Itachi, you also serve as the Uchiha clan's
pipeline to the village nerve center.
You know that, don't you?
Yes.
Well, make sure you don't forget it.
You will be at that meeting tomorrow.
Sasuke.
Use the bathroom and go to sleep.
Okay.
What are you doing roaming the house at
this hour?
Get to bed!
Yes, sir.
Father only cares about you, Itachi.
You probably hate me, huh?
It's alright.
People often think ill of Shinobi.
It's only logical.
That's not how I feel.
He's right, though.
I do... I do feel that way.
Being the best isn't all it's cracked up
to be.
When you have power, you become arrogant
and isolated from the world.
No matter how coveted and sought after you
are in the beginning.
But with us, it's different, because you
and I are flesh and blood.
I'm always going to
be there for you, even if
it's only as an obstacle
for you to overcome.
Even if you do hate me.
That's what big brothers are for.
Is Itachi in there?
We need to talk!
Get out here!
What's going on?
What are you all doing here?
There were two people who didn't show up
at yesterday's assembly.
Do you want to tell me why you weren't
there?
The meeting Father was talking about last
night... He didn't go after all.
You're in the Anbu Black Ops now.
I know full well you can be called away at
the drop of a hat.
And that's the case
your father was trying
to make when we asked
why you weren't there.
But we're not your father.
You won't be getting any special treatment
from us.
I understand.
I should have been more careful.
Will that be all, then, gentlemen?
Sure thing.
But you know what?
Before we go, there's just one other
thing.
Do you know anything about Shisui Uchiha
ending his life in Nagano River?
Ending his life?
Shisui was the other guy who never turned
up at the assembly yesterday.
It's funny.
If I remember correctly, you kind of
looked up to him like an older brother,
didn't you?
How terrible.
Forgive me, I haven't seen him at all
recently.
What a tragedy.
Yeah.
Well, at this point, the police
force sees no other choice
but to launch an all-out
investigation into the matter.
Investigation?
This is a note Shisui left behind.
We've already had it analyzed.
There's no question this is his
handwriting.
But if it wasn't homicide, why the
investigation?
It would be no great
feat for someone who
possesses Sharingan
to copy his handwriting.
The most talented of all our clan.
Feared as Shisui the Teleporter,
he was a man who would do anything,
take any mission, if it was for the good
of the clan.
Hard to imagine a man like that ending his
life, don't you think?
You shouldn't judge people by their
appearance, or by your own preconceptions.
We'll leave that with you for the time
being.
Take it to Anbu Black
Ops, and put in a request
for them to start snipping
around on this as well.
Understood.
Let's just hope we get a lead on this
soon.
By the way, we have our own connections
inside of Anbu Black Ops.
You try and sweep this investigation under
the rug, and we're gonna know about it.
Why don't you just come out and say it?
You believe I had a hand in this,
don't you?
Yeah, that's right, little punk.
Listen, Itachi.
If I find you betrayed this clan, I want
you to know, you'll pay for your wrongs.
Like I said before, appearances and
preconceptions aren't going to tell you anything.
For instance, you've made the mistake of
assuming I'm a patient man.
The clan, the clan.
You overestimate your own abilities,
with no idea of the depth of my own.
And look at you now, groveling in the
dirt.
I've never seen him like this before.
The strangeness of your behavior.
Half a year into your time at Anbu,
it was impossible to overlook.
What the heck are you playing at,
you filthy little wretch?
Obsessed with the organization.
Obsessed with the clan.
Obsessed with our lineage.
A worthless compulsion that enslaves us,
and limits our capabilities.
Leading us to fear what you don't
understand.
Stop it, Itachi!
What on earth is the matter with you?
Itachi, you've been strange lately.
Huh?
I've had enough.
There's no hope left for this pathetic
clan.
The people of this clan are all the same.
You focus on the trivial and lose sight of
what's most important.
Change is impossible in this fog of
ignorance.
How can we evolve when regulation is all
we know?
Such arrogance!
That's enough!
If I hear one more word of this nonsense,
I'll have you thrown behind bars!
Brother, why?
Well, what's it gonna be?
I can't take this anymore.
Please sir, just give me the order!
Big brother, you have to stop!
I'm not the one who killed Shisui, but I
apologize for the words I have spoken.
I'm truly sorry.
He's been pretty tired lately, after his
years in missions from the Anbu Black Ops.
But Captain!
Anbu are under the direct control of the
Hokage.
Even if you wanted to arrest one of them,
you would need to get a warrant first.
I take full responsibility for him.
You've my word.
Very well, sir.
What did it mean?
That look in my brother's eyes...
That was no ordinary Sharingan.
And ever since, even
though that was a while ago,
there's been something
wrong between him and father.
Good morning to you, father.
Ah, yes.
Good morning.
How's everything going at the academy?
Some of the lessons are a little boring,
but I'm always top of my class.
Fire style!
Fireball jutsu!
Whoa!
This is the key jutsu of our clan.
Now I've already shown you all the hand
signs.
The next step is to build up your chakra
and focus it to a point in your chest,
then force it up through the throat and
out the mouth.
Now you try it.
Right!
Father's actually teaching me the jutsu
himself.
He's finally giving me a chance to show
that I matter too.
I can't disappoint him.
Fire style!
Fireball jutsu!
Why did I think you would be like Itachi?
It's too soon.
They're not ready yet.
A member of the Uchiha
clan is not recognized as
full-fledged until they
can use the fire style.
The Uchiha crest represents the fan that
rouses the flame of our will.
Fire style!
Fireball jutsu!
Okay, today for sure.
Fire style!
Fireball jutsu!
Sasuke?
Hold on a minute.
What is it?
What's that for?
No, no, don't go yet.
There, that should help.
Hey, mom?
No, it's nothing.
You sure?
I'm just getting started.
Okay, here we go.
Fire style!
Fireball jutsu!
Father!
Just once more?
Will you come watch me one more time?
I told you it's too soon for you.
I could teach you every day for a week and
it wouldn't help.
No, not teach me.
Watch me.
I'm saying I think I've got the hang of
it, father.
Failure is not an option.
Fire style!
Fireball jutsu!
Now then, that's my boy.
You've done well.
Work hard and you're bound to soar high.
And to bring honor to that crest you wear
on your back.
I will!
From now on, walk your own path.
Not in the footsteps of your brother.
Hey, mom.
I was wondering, about Itachi and me,
what does father really think of us?
What on earth makes you ask that?
It was something he said.
The other day, down on the dock,
father said to me, that's my boy.
That's something he's only ever said to
Itachi.
So it made me really happy to hear it.
Of course, and I'm glad it did.
But then I started to wonder, now that
father and Itachi aren't getting along...
Am I just... someone to replace my older
brother?
Your older brother's your older brother,
and you're you.
But your father has always cared very
deeply about both of you.
He's only thought of Itachi before now!
Well, if it sometimes
seemed that way, it's only
because your father is a
leader of the Uchiha clan.
He has to make sure it's kept safe.
What's that got to do with it?
Your brother is the firstborn,
and he's bigger than you are.
And as the firstborn,
he's going to have to
assume his responsibilities
earlier than you will.
So since it's your father's job to look
after the clan, it's only natural he'd
want to be sure that Itachi's ready to
take on his role.
But I'll let you in on a secret.
When we're alone and no one's around,
the only one he talks about is you.
He has a hard time showing it.
It's how he is.
Big brother!
Do you... think you could help me out with
my shuriken jutsu after school today?
No, I can't.
I'm busy.
Why don't you go ask father to help you?
Aw, come on.
You're better at the shuriken jutsu than
father is.
I mean, even I can see that.
Big brother, why do you always treat me
like such a pest?
I'm sorry, Sasuke.
Some other time, okay?
I don't have time for this today.
You're always doing this to me.
You jab me in the forehead and then say
I'm sorry, Sasuke.
And you never have time.
It's always the same story.
Father?
How come... how come big brother never
pays any attention to me?
Your brother's always been a little
strange, son.
He has a hard time dropping his guard
around other people, letting them in.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
Even I can't read him.
And I'm the boy's father.
That kid.
Okay, here's your lunch, Sasuke.
And as for your shuriken
practice, I can help
you work on it when
you get home if you want.
It's not just practice.
It's actual training.
See you later!
Good morning, Sasuke.
Heading off to school now, are you?
Uh-huh.
I saw your brother earlier.
He's grown into such a man.
He's an excellent shinobi, isn't he?
Graduating the academy at the age of seven
and first in his class.
And he was a chunin at ten, wasn't he?
Yeah, and he could use Sharingan by the
time he was eight.
That's right.
How could I forget?
That boy is the pride of the Uchiha clan.
No doubt about it.
What about you, Sasuke?
How old are you now?
I'm the same age as my brother when he
graduated.
And I'm...
What's the matter, child?
Honey!
Stop talking nonsense to the boy,
will you?
What do you mean, dear?
Sasuke, both you and
Itachi are of the Uchiha
clan, the brightest gem
of the Hidden Leaf Village.
Have faith in yourself.
Someday you'll be an outstanding shinobi,
just like Itachi.
See you later!
Just do your best!
Study hard now and you'll do fine!
I won't lose to him!
I'm so late!
What was that?
I could have sworn there was someone
there.
Huh?
What is going on?
What is happening?
Aunty?
Oh no!
Father and mother!
Somebody's in here!
Move!
Father!
Mother!
Big brother!
Itachi!
Father and mother are both... I don't...
understand... Who could do all this?
What have you done?
Big brother!
Foolish little brother.
I almost pity you.
Mangekyou Sharingan!
I can't move my legs!
No!
Stop it!
Itachi!
Why are you showing me all this?
Why did you do this, brother?
No!
Aunty!
Uncle!
Father!
Mother!
Stop it, Itachi!
Father and mother!
No!
Why?
Why did you do this?
Itachi, why?
To test the limits of my ability.
To test your ability?
That's why you did this?
You're telling me that was why you
butchered them?
You're out of your mind!
I'm scared.
I'm scared!
Please!
I don't want to die!
Why?
It's a lie.
This isn't like you, big brother.
It can't be.
I have acted like the older brother you
desired for one reason.
Because I wanted to discover how powerful
you were.
I needed to find a worthy opponent to test
the limits of my own abilities.
You have that unique potential.
Now I've made you hate me.
Now you have the desire to defeat me.
Which is exactly why I'm going to allow
you to live.
Don't you see?
It's all for my own benefit.
Like me, you may be one of the few who can
use Mangekyou Sharingan.
But there is a catch.
Take the life of your best friend.
You must kill him.
No, that's a lie.
Kill him, just like I did.
Itachi, you killed Shisui.
I did.
How else do you think I obtained these
powers?
In the main hall of Nakano Shrine,
underneath the seventh tatami mat from the
far right, is the clan's secret gathering
place.
There you will find a secret document,
an explanation of the Uchiha clan's jutsu.
It tells of the visual jutsu's true
purpose.
What?
The true purpose?
If you discover how to
activate it, you will be the third
person to obtain the Mangekyou
Sharingan, including myself.
To ensure that happens, that's enough
reason to let you live.
Well, that's all.
Oh, don't worry.
You're not worth killing.
My foolish little brother, if you wish to
kill me one day, in hate and revenge,
surviving in such an unsightly manner as
this, by all means flee.
Cling to your wretched life.
And then, one day, when you possess the
same eyes, come back and face me.
Huh?
No, wait!
Yeah, that's what I heard too.
That boy was the only one who survived the
massacre.
Someone said they think he has an older
brother.
Is that right?
Yeah, he does.
But no one knows where he is right now.
I can't believe it.
That the elite Uchiha clan could just
be...
Hello there, Sasuke.
What tasty treats can I get for you today?
Huh?
In
the main hall of Nakano Shrine,
underneath the seventh tatami mat on the
far right, is the clan's secret gathering
place.
I see now.
So that's what it all means.
What do you say, Shikamaru?
Wanna go to the candy store after school?
Huh?
No way!
You can get away with that stuff cause
your mom's nice.
But if my mother found
out I didn't come straight
home, man, I'd be in
some serious trouble.
Did you hear?
Apparently the entire Uchiha clan was
murdered.
Yeah, that's what my dad was telling me.
They say that Sasuke is the only one who
survived.
Now then, that's my boy.
When we're alone and no one's around,
the only one he talks about is you.
I wish I knew what kinds of things he said
to her about me.
If you wish to kill me one day,
in hate and revenge...
Brother!
No matter what darkness may await me, if it
means killing you, I will meet it head on.
And whatever happens, I will get that
power.
From this point on, I am an Avenger.
Wherever he is, Sasuke is in the darkness.
If we all stay put here, we won't be able
to catch up with him.
Eiji, it's just like you said.
Sasuke is in the depths of darkness right
now.
He really wants to kill me.
I can't believe it.
What am I to you now?
We were comrades, or have you just
forgotten all about that?
Are you telling me that all
the things we did together
in Squad 7 mean absolutely
nothing to you now?
They weren't meaningless.
One thing was worthwhile.
Our friendship.
We became best friends.
We became best friends?
Then why are we fighting?
I just told you.
Because we're friends, there's far more
meaning in destroying you.
I can't understand that.
But what I know is that for some reason,
you want to destroy me.
Right, Sasuke?
I know I said this already, but...
Be honest with yourself.
You've been waiting for this moment too.
Kakashi and Sakura aren't here now.
Nobody's gonna stop us like the last time.
You lousy...
Midori!
You idiot!
Right back at ya, pal!
I'll beat you into oblivion if that's what
it's gonna take to bring you back home!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Rasengan!
He
was able to counter my Chidori at its full
power.
Naruto...
So, looks like you're good for two bursts.
That's about your limit.
What would happen if I tried to use it
more than twice?
Well, for one thing, it wouldn't work.
But remember this.
If you try to force a Jutsu,
not only will it not work,
but the attempt can drain
your chakra to absolute zero.
Worst case scenario, you die.
I can't waste another blow.
It would be pointless.
All we'll do is cancel each other out
again.
That's it.
There's no mistaking it now.
You're dead serious about this,
aren't you?
You really mean to...
I'll have to use some of my faster Jutsu
to create an opening.
And then... I'll hit him with Chidori.
Sasuke...
Sasuke... You know what
they say, don't you, Naruto?
When two shinobi are
powerful enough, they are able to
read each other's thoughts
simply by an exchange of fists.
Tell me, do you know my thoughts?
Can you tell what's on my mind?
Fire Style!
Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
Sasuke... I always knew that you were
alone.
At first, when I realized there was someone
else like me around, I was relieved.
And happy, too.
To tell the truth, I wanted to approach
you right off the bat.
But... I just couldn't work up the nerve.
You were always able to do everything.
And everyone was always fawning over you.
But... You were
so far ahead of me.
And I didn't want to admit it.
So I started to see you as my rival.
I didn't want to lose to you.
And with everyone calling me a loser,
it just made things worse.
Even when we became Squad Seven,
I never stopped feeling that way.
I was stubborn.
And I couldn't express what I really felt.
The truth was, I really just wanted to be
like you.
You were... You were everything I aspired
to.
That's why...
You're one of the ones I want to fight the
most.
You have no idea how happy you made me
that day.
It was the first time you ever said
anything acknowledging me.
You and I don't need to come to blows to
know each other's thoughts anyway.
Ever since that day, even though we've
never said it.
There's no question.
You're my closest friend.
But now, you're seriously trying to take
me out.
And I don't really know if you meant to be
said before or not.
Maybe I was the only one.
Who thought... Who thought that we were
friends?
I told you it's too late!
If that's the case, then...
Then how stupid am I?
I don't know why.
But...
But I...
I just can't bear the thought...
Of seeing you taken away by someone like
Orochimaru!
You managed to divert the blow with your
left hand at the last second.
But in the end, it doesn't matter,
does it?
You're finished anyway.
You can forget all about hand signs and
that jutsu of yours.
This is the end.
You're finished.
What is this power?
And what was that red chakra?
Is he some kind of monster?
I've had enough of this.
What the heck are you?
I'm your friend!
That's why I'm telling you...
I'm not going to let the likes of
Orochimaru get a hold of you!
And if you won't listen to reason,
then... I'll break every bone in your body!
Fire Style!
Fireball Jutsu!
Now let's go!
Enough is enough!
Snap out of it already!
If you don't come to your senses,
then I'm just going to have to break all
your bones and drag you back to the
village!
So get up, Sasuke!
Just shut up for once.
What the heck do you know about it?
It's not like you ever had a family in the
first place!
You were on your own right from the
beginning!
What makes you think you know anything
about it, huh?!
I'm suffering now because I had those
ties.
How on earth could you possibly understand
what it feels like to lose all that?!
It's true.
I have no idea what it's like having
parents or a brother.
But... It's my treat today.
Eat as much as you want.
Alright!
Why?!
Whenever I'm with Iruka-sensei,
I wonder...
DOWN THE HATCH!
First of all, a ninja's gotta have
sustenance!
Hey, take it easy.
Don't whoop it down so fast.
I wonder if that's what it feels like to
have a father.
And when I'm with you...
Whatever, you moron!
What the heck is your problem,
you loser?
There's no way I'm gonna lose to you!
Yeah, keep talking.
Gotcha!
Just get off me.
I wonder if this is what it feels like to
have a brother.
Why, Naruto?
Why would you go so far from me?
Because this is the first time I've ever
had a bond like this.
That's why I'll do anything I can to stop
you!
It's too late, Naruto.
It's just too late.
I can't turn back.
Come, Naruto!
If that's how it is, I'll just have to
sever that bond.
Sever it just like that, huh?
Then why do you even bother wearing that
headband anymore?
I'll admit it.
You're definitely strong.
It's because you know the pain that
solitude brings, just as I do.
It's that very pain that makes you and I
stronger, Naruto.
Which means if I can
just break that bond,
I'll be able to achieve
even greater strength.
It's time you and I had this out,
as equals.
But you're still not going to be able to
lay even a single scratch on my forehead.
I know that hasn't changed at least.
Fine.
Guess there's no point in talking anymore.
Sasuke!
Enough.
No more words.
From here on out, we stick to fight.
Come!
I can see...
His moves that were too fast for me
before.
I can see them now.
I can see...
With every step, every
subtle shift in his momentum,
the image of his next
move becomes vividly clear.
As long as I have these eyes, I don't need
to expend any chakra.
The curse mark would eat up too much of
it.
With vision like this, I can
make out the image of Naruto's
every move before it happens,
and time my attacks accordingly.
This isn't good.
He's totally reading my movements.
What do I do?
Sasuke!
Flare Style!
Dragon Flame Jutsu!
Sasuke...
It's too late, Naruto.
It's too late now!
Naruto!
You're weak.
You better be grateful to me...
and to your beloved fourth Hokage,
who sealed me inside a twerp like you.
Naruto!
What was that?
I can still read his movements.
This chakra...
It's... it's almost like it has a mind of
its own.
Even my eyes can't follow it.
That red aura... that's no ordinary
chakra.
I know that he's the one you're really
after.
You're right.
Naruto is the prize that the Akatsuki are
after.
And we will have him.
I see.
So you have some kind of special power
then.
I think I understand now!
Fire Style!
Fireball Jutsu!
That chakra is protecting him?
As long as I keep my distance,
I'll be fine.
But what is he?
All I can do is dodge.
Oh well.
No getting around it, I guess.
Once I go ahead and let this power take
over...
I... I'm not all that sure what will
happen to me in the end.
But you're not leaving me a lot of choice
here, Naruto.
There's no question that you're special.
Unfortunately, you're not quite as special
as I am.
Hehehehe...
Sasuke...
So you're special, huh?
You won't be so special when I'm finished
with you!
Hehehehe...
There's no way I'm gonna lose!
No!
Sasuke!
You're a monster!
My body... I guess I can't waste any more
time.
My left arm... I can't feel it anymore!
That power of yours...
By using it, you're taking a risk,
aren't you?
Look around.
You know where we are?
It's called the Final Valley.
The perfect setting for this fight.
Isn't it, Naruto?
Well...
Oh right, of course.
I said there'd be no more talking,
didn't I?
In that case, I guess we're at the end.
The end of this fight.
And all the fights up to now.
Chidori!
The End
And this is the second one.
And this is the third one.
And this is the fourth one.
And Naruto would battle it out here.
It's pretty ironic, don't you think?
Yeah.
Look at that river.
The water just rages on for eternity.
Like this epic, never-ending battle.
As eternal as the two founders of the
Hidden Leaf Village.
Forever standing as these statues.
Naruto and Sasuke.
As long as they live, the cycle will
continue.
Naruto and Sasuke Take the life of your
best friend.
You must kill him.
No, brother.
Just because you say it, doesn't mean I'm
gonna listen.
I will get my hands on that power.
But not the way you want me to.
I'm going to surpass you.
But I'll do it my way.
I will.
The storm.
It finally broke.
All that rain.
I won't be able to follow his scent.
But keeping Naruto alive is more important
than finding Sasuke.
Yeah.
Where's Sasuke?
Kakashi!
What's Naruto Uzumaki's condition?
He'll pull through.
And Sasuke?
Sasuke Uchiha?
What about him?
What happened?
How are the other genin?
Oh, right.
Lady Hokage dispatched the First and
Second Medical Corps to pick them up.
Emergency treatment was administered on
the scene.
Then they were all immediately
transported... to the hospital.
They were all wounded?
Yes.
Shikamaru Nara is doing fine.
Only minor injuries.
Kiba Inuzukas are more serious,
but not life-threatening.
However, Neji Hyuga and Choji Akimichi are
both in critical condition.
At this point, they could go either way.
Everyone...
It's all here.
Thoroughly researched.
The medications, their effects,
and ingredients.
This is excellent.
I'm gonna need more of the deer antler.
Yes, milady.
Well, sis, how is he?
He's fine.
Well, no long walks for him anytime soon,
that's for sure.
Can't you do anything for him?
You're a vet!
Not a magician.
It takes time.
But relax, his life's not in danger.
No long walks for you anytime soon,
either.
I got it.
Don't worry.
Aww...
We've been at it almost three hours.
Your turn to take over.
Okay.
We're using the boy's own hair as a
conductor, so focus on that.
Try to accelerate the growth rate of the
injured cells.
Right.
As for the chakra control, just think of
threading a needle.
Yes, I understand.
A few hours later...
No point in making yourself crazy,
you know.
Don't you remember your psychological
training?
With every mission comes sacrifice.
Training and reality are two different
things.
I thought I knew about missions.
I thought I knew what it meant to be a
shinobi.
Now, after this mission, my first as a
squad leader...
Only one thing's clear.
I'm just not cut out to be a shinobi.
Honestly, all you men with such fragile
egos.
This mission... I thought all I had to do
was depend on everybody else.
Some leader... I should have done more,
but I didn't have the strength.
It's all my fault.
What are you afraid you might get hurt?
Shikamaru... A girl disrespects
you like that and you just walk away?
You bet I do.
Standing around arguing's not my thing.
That's something girls like to do.
And what are you?
Not a man, that's for sure.
Far as I can see, you're nothing but a
coward.
You think if you quit, the missions will
stop?
Someone's gotta do it.
Your comrades will be
sent out again on other
missions, with someone
else leading them.
They'll face the same risks, and some of
them might not make it.
Ones you might have saved if you'd been
there to lead them.
How are you going to feel then?
You've got a chance to reflect on your
mistakes and to learn from them.
Use your failures to make yourself a
better leader.
You won't help your friends by running
away.
Instead, you should be trying to make
yourself stronger, for their sake.
So that the next mission goes perfectly,
and everyone gets back safe.
The choice is simple, you're either a
leader or a coward.
So, which are you?
Ah...
He's gonna be just fine.
The antidote worked.
The extermination of cells caused by the
pill's effects has been arrested.
I couldn't have done it without your help,
Shikaku.
The Nara Clan's Sacred Medicine Guide was
invaluable.
The work that went into that manual,
the years of research...
Well, it's quite impressive, to say the
least.
Thank you.
Lady Tsunami!
Neji Hyuga is safe.
His condition has stabilized.
And there's more.
I've just heard that
Kakashi Hatake and Naruto
Uzumaki have returned
and they've been examined.
Naruto's injuries are serious,
but not life-threatening.
He's going to be okay.
Shikamaru... Just two...
Shikamaru, your mission was a failure.
However, everyone's alive.
That's the most important thing.
Next time, the mission will go perfectly.
Sasuke... Sasuke, you
are the chosen one.
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
When are you going to give me the power?
A word of advice.
Watch what you say if you want to live
long.
Don't let his physical appearance fool
you.
That's still Lord Orochimaru you're
talking to.
The intensity of his chakra...
Yes, he's the one.
My future lies in him.
Well, well.
So you're awake, huh?
Shikamaru!
I was going to go check in on Choji and
see how he's doing.
How about you?
I just thought I'd look in on Naruto.
And Sasuke, if he's there.
I see.
Well, at least everybody's okay.
That's good.
So... so Sasuke's... Yeah.
He's gone.
So they're still not letting anyone in to
see him?
No.
But they say he'll be regaining
consciousness soon enough.
He'll be alright.
Thank goodness.
It was a fortunate day for this village
when Lady Tsunade agreed to come back.
If it weren't for her, Choji would have...
Lady Tsunade.
The fifth Hokage.
Here for a visit?
News travels fast, I see.
Sakura!
Naruto...
I'd heard that your injuries were pretty
serious.
You seem to be doing well, considering.
I'm... sorry, Sakura.
Sorry?
What have you got to be sorry about?
Let me guess.
You got reckless and went off half-cocked
again, huh?
Look at you now.
You look like a mummy.
I'm... so sorry.
Hey, why do you have the curtains closed?
It's a beautiful day outside.
See?
I haven't given up.
Listen, I'm still gonna keep my promise.
After all, it was the promise of a
lifetime, right?
I meant it!
It's okay, Naruto.
Really.
He tried, Sakura.
If I say I'm gonna do it, that means I
will, okay?
Don't forget, my way of the shinobi means
I always stand behind what I say!
Naruto...
Thanks, Naruto.
I've gotta focus on healing these injuries
if I'm gonna bring Sasuke back.
Huh?
What the heck is that?
Pervy Sage?
Hey there.
What I have to tell you is important.
It can't wait.
From now on, you're my only student.
I need to make a full-fledged shinobi out
of you in three years, and I'll do it.
But why three years?
We've received some disturbing information
regarding the Akatsuki.
Akatsuki?
We've reasoned to believe you've been
chosen as their next target, and we have
three or four years before they come after
you.
No way, that's not gonna work!
I don't have time for that!
Do you think I care about what might
happen three years down the road?
What are you talking about?
Orochimaru's already got his hands on
Sasuke, and his life is in danger right now!
That's what I'm talking about!
I see you know all the gruesome details of
Orochimaru's little scheme.
Wait, you mean you knew all about it too?
Well, of course.
Don't you think I've been studying that
immortality jutsu of his?
That's also how I know our good friend
Orochimaru won't be able to reincarnate
himself in another body for at least three
more years.
Fortunately, he ran out
of time and had to take
over another body before
Sasuke could get there.
That means Sasuke is safe for three years.
So you do have time.
Really?
Are you sure of that, Purvey Sage?
Are you absolutely sure?
Yeah.
Forget Sasuke.
You can't help him, so just forget about
him.
Sasuke went to Orochimaru of his own free
will.
No matter what you do, he will not change.
I've seen many shinobi, so I know the
type.
Orochimaru and Sasuke are cut from the
same cloth.
Don't delude yourself into thinking that
you can bring him back.
You can't.
It's hopeless.
A fool's errand.
Maybe it's easy for you to give up on him,
Purvey Sage, but I can't!
He may mean nothing to you, but he's my
friend!
Idiot!
Just take a good look at the condition you're
in, and he's the one who did it to you!
Was that the work of a friend?
No, but.
..
Why?
Why are you doing this?
You and I have been comrades since
childhood.
Together we're part of the three legendary
Sannin.
What a sentimental fool you are,
Jiraiya.
You always were blind to reality.
You couldn't see, couldn't imagine what I
was really doing all along.
It's not too late to turn back,
Orochimaru.
Don't do this.
How'd you get to be such a fool?
All my pleading meant nothing.
He left us and would never return.
After the pain, all I was left with was a
sense of helplessness and regret.
Above all, I want to save you from going
through that, Naruto.
If you insist on going after Sasuke,
then you'll get no training from me.
I'll have the Anbu Black
Ops assigned to guard
you, to prevent you
from leaving the village.
You're not just some ordinary kid.
You've got something inside you the
Akatsuki want, the Nine-Tailed Fox.
But if you're going to behave like a kid
and not listen to what I tell you,
then I'll do what I have to do.
Eventually, you're going to
face enemies far worse than
Orochimaru, and it's time
you started preparing for them.
The first thing is for you to give up on
Sasuke.
What happened was destined to happen.
Dismiss him from your mind and move on.
To be a shinobi, you need more than
strength and jutsu.
You must acquire the judgment to make the
right decisions.
You must become smarter.
The longer you remain a fool, the harder
it will be for you to live in this world.
Fine, then.
If being smarter means what you say it
does, I'll remain a fool my entire life.
I'm going after him, and I'll do it alone
if I have to!
I'll create my own incredible jutsu,
and whenever the Akatsuki show up,
I'll smack them down!
Go!
The thought of my leaving you to
come up with jutsu on your own...
like that idiotic, sexy jutsu of
yours... no, it's too depressing.
This is more than foolish.
It's so colossally foolish, it might even
work.
We've got a lot of work
to do when you get out of
the hospital, so be ready
to hit the ground running!
See you then.
You got it!